A Finding Aid to the Milton Wolf Brown Papers, 1908-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.browmilt
Archives of American Art
- Writings, circa 1929-1990s; Series 4; (Boxes 4-13, 25; 8.7 linear feet)
  - Lectures, circa 1950-1991; 4.3
    This subseries contains lecture files maintained by Milton Brown, which may include draft versions of his lectures, slide lists, related correspondence, and event announcements and programs. Also found are memorial addresses for colleagues written by Brown. Researchers should note that Brown often gave different versions of the same lectures at various museums, symposiums, universities, and art organizations. Common topics of his lectures included the Armory Show, the "Emergence of the Machine Image in American Art," and "The Eight and the Ashcan School," and "Social Activism." Files are arranged alphabetically by lecture location.
    - Memorial Addresses, circa 1973-1991 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "The Armory Show" (Multiple Versions), circa 1963-1988; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
    - "The Eight and the Ashcan School" (Multiple Versions), undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - "The History of Photography as Art History,", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - "The Emergence of the Machine Image" (Multiple Versions), undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "Social Activism,", circa 1982 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, "Art As Activist: Jacob Lawrence and Social Realism,", 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - American Historical Association, "The Little Renaissance,", 1952 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - American Association of Appraisers, "The Armory Show,", 1988 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Archives of American Art, "The Emergence of the Machine Image in American Art,", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Brooklyn College, "Paradoxes,", undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Brooklyn Museum, "The Eight and the Ashcan School,", 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Brooklyn Museum, "First Wave of Modernism,", 1957 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Brooklyn Museum, "Lewis Hine,", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Brooklyn Museum, "20th Century Painting,", 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Burchfield Art Center, "Charles Burchfield and American Realism,", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - College Art Association, "Early Collections of Modern Art in the U.S.,", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - College Art Association, "Marxism in the USA,", circa late-1980s (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - City University of New York, "The Emergence of the Machine Image in American Art in the Early 20th Century,", 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, "The Emergence of the Machine Image in American Art,", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, "The Story of the Armory Show,", 1985 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, "Modernism in America: The First Wave,", 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Edinburgh International Festival, "The Modern Spirit,", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Grand Rapids Art Museum, "The Armory Show,", 1966 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Greenwich Library, "The Armory Show Revisited: The Role of Cos Cob,", 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Greystone, "Colonial Architecture,", undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Grinnell College, "The Question of Jewish Painting in 20th Century American Art,", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Henry Luce Foundation Symposium, Keynote Address, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Hirshhorn Museum, "The Eight and The Ashcan School,", 1975 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Hirshhorn Museum, "Post Offices, Train Stations, and Public Places: Art of the 30s,", 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Institute of Fine Arts, "Art Nouveau,", 1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Institute of Fine Arts, Walter Cook Tribute, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - IFA Student Club, "On Teaching,", undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - IFA Student Club, "Vermeer,", undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - International Communication Association, "Introduction to Painting in the United States,", 1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Museum, "The Emergence of the Jewish Artist in the U.S. in the 20th Century,", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Long Island University, "The Early Hartley: The Armory Show,", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, "The Eight Group,", 1966 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "Abbeys and Churches of England,", undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "As They Once Were: MMA Paintings and Their Complements,", undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "The Joseph H. Hirshhorn Collection: From the Depression to the End of World War II,", 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "Mexico,", 1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "Paul Strand,", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "West Pilgrimage Route,", 1956 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Morris Museum of Arts and Sciences, "The Eight and the Ashcan School,", 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Montclair Art Museum, Lecture on the Soyers, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Museum of Art, Fort Lauderdale, "The Eight and the Ashcan School,", 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - National Gallery of Art, "The Armory show of 1913,", 1971 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - National Gallery of Art, "Art and Social Activism in the Thirties,", 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - National Gallery of Art, "Emergence of the Machine Image in American Art of the Early 20th Century,", 1989 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art, "Social Activism in the Art of the 1930s,", 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - North Shore Community Arts Center, "The Joseph H. Hirshhorn Collection: From the Depression to the End of World War II,", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Oklahoma Art Center, "Charles Burchfield and American Realism,", 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Provincetown Playhouse, "The Armory Show,", 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Ringling Museum of Art, "Contemporary American Art,", 1956 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, "Dynamic Symmetry,", 1961 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Rutgers University and Whitney Museum, "From Sloan to Hopper: Positivism into Alienation,", 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Southern Illinois University, "The Influence of the Armory Show on the Art of the Twenties,", 1969 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, "Social Activism in American Art of the 1930s,", 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - University of Delaware, "American Modernism and the Machine Age,", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - University of Delaware, Symposium Keynote, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - University of Texas at Arlington, "Art and Diplomacy: Problems of International Exhibitions,", 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Whitney Museum, "Art of the 30s: Social Protest,", 1968 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Williams College, "Prendergast Redux,", 1990 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Yale University, "Cultural Issues in American Painting Since 1913,", undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Writings for Publication, 1943-1994; 4.4
    Found here are Milton Brown's writings for publication, including exhibition catalog essays, essays for art publications, entries for encyclopedias, and journal and magazine articles. Folders may include draft writings, copies of the published version, notes, and related correspondence. Of note are Brown's draft scripts and related material for his work on the BBC program "100 Great Paintings."
    - Catalog Essay, "Duncan Phillips: Adventure in Art,", 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Catalog Essay, "Ed Wiener, Craftsman/Artist,", undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Catalog Essay, "Jozef Pilage,", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Catalog Essay, "Lois Dodd,", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Catalog Essay, "Moses and Ida Soyer Collection,", 1971 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Catalog Essay, "Robert Gwathmey,", 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Catalog Essay, "Walter Quirt,", undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Catalog Essay, "Walter Rosenblum,", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Essay, New York Observed, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Essay, Social Art in America: 1930-1945, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Essays, World Book Encyclopedia, circa 1958 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Foreword, New York WPA Artists, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Introduction for Jack Levine, 1986-1990; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 48-49)
    - Scripts, "100 Great Paintings,", 1978-1985; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 50-52)
    - Text for "Paul Strand, Wall Street, New York, 1915,", 1983 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - "American Art," The International Illustrated Encyclopedia of Art, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - "Armory Show," S. I. G. N. A. L. E., 1988-1989, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - "The Armory Show and Its Aftermath," 1915, The Cultural Moment, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - "Cubist-Realism: An American Style," Marsyas 3, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "An Explosion of Creativity: Jews in American Art in the 20th Century," Painting a Place in America, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "I Remember MOMA," Art News, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Marxist Approach to Art," Critics Group, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Paul Strand," Photography Year Book, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Paul Strand: The Three Roads," Paul Strand: Essays on His Life and Work, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Raphael Soyer (1899-1987)," Jewish Currents, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Reading Lists," Art News, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Realism in the United States Between the Two Wars," Les Realismes entre Revolution et Reaction, 1919-1939, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "The 75th Anniversary of the Armory Show," Archives of American Art Journal, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "The Tastemongers," Challenge, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - General Research Notes and Writings, circa 1940s-1990s; 4.5
    Found here are various address lists, loose notes, primarily on the subject of art history, and a series of notecards. The notecards have been kept in Milton Brown's original file arrangement. The purpose of these notecards is not indicated, but they may have been used for one or more of his book projects. Also found here are five computer floppy disks which are unlabeled.
    - Address Lists, circa 1990s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Notes, 1947, undated; (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 13-16)
    - Notecards, undated; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
    - Notecards, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Computer Disks (Unlabeled), undated; (5 1/4-inch floppy disks; 5 disks) (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Student Writings and Notes, circa 1929-1939; 4.6
    This subseries contains Milton Brown's notes and writing assignments from high school, New York University, and Harvard University's Fogg Art Museum course. Also found is one file of class notes belonging to his wife, Blanche Brown.
    - Class Assignments, circa 1933-1939; (7 folders) (Box 11, Folder 20-26)
    - Class Notes and Syllabi, circa 1934-1937; (6 folders) (Box 11, Folder 27-32)
    - High School Papers, circa 1929 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Short Stories, 1932, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Blanche Brown, Class Notes, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1930s-1991; 4.7
    Writings by others include draft essays, book chapters, and articles sent to Milton Brown from his colleagues. Many of these writings have a cover letter written to Brown from the author requesting his review and feedback. Also found here are course outlines and handouts written by notable art history professors such as Erwin Panofsky, Walter Friedlander, and Walter Cook.
    - Deirdre Barber, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Nancy Boas, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Ruth Bowman, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Blanche Brown, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Stephen Brown, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Michael Corris, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tom DeHaven, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - James Marston Fitch, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Cissy Grossman, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Andrew Hemingway, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Carl Holty, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - J. B. J., 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Jim M. Jordan, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Jules Kabat, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Ben Maddow, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Mark Bendor, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Francis V. O'Connor, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Hilla Rebay, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Ad Reinhardt, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Jack Rennert, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Naomi Rosenblum, circa 1980 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Aline Saarinen, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Dimitri Sarabanov, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Meyer Schapiro, 1931-1949 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - David Shapiro, circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 22-23)
    - Elaine Shefer, circa 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Elinor Sprague, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Marion Summers, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Unknown Author, "HS Music Program,", 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Writings by Unknown Authors, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - College Course Outlines and Handouts (Box 12)
      - Walter Cook, circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Walter Friedlander, circa 1930s; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 30-31)
      - Erwin Panofsky, circa 1930s; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 32-33)
      - Jakob Rosenberg, 1938-1939; (1 of 2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Jakob Rosenberg, 1938-1939; (2 of 2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - William Sawitzky, circa 1930s (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Prendergast Catalogue Raisonne Project, circa 1952-1990; Series 5; (Boxes 13-14, 25; 1.8 linear feet)
  This series contains Milton Brown's Prendergast Catalogue Raisonne Project files. Brown was appointed senior fellow for the project at Williams College from 1983 to 1987. Found here are project documents such as correspondence, draft essays by Brown and others, notes, outlines, bibliographies, budgets, and reports. Also found are research files on Prendergast compiled for the project including notes from twenty separate meetings with Mrs. Prendergast, as well as genealogical documents, auction lists, photocopies of exhibition catalogs and other printed material.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - "Alphabetical Listing of Works,", 1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - American Art Research Council Files on Prendergast (Photocopies), circa 1940s (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Auction Lists, circa 1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Bibliographic Research Material, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1990; (5 folders) (Box 13, Folder 7-11)
  - Data Entry Documentation, circa 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation, Maurice Prendergast: The Sources and Development of His Style by Hedley H. Rhys, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Draft Essays, circa 1986-1989; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
  - Drafts of Catalogue Raisonne Front Matter, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Essay, "Maurice B. Prendergast,", circa 1980s; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
  - Exhibition Catalog, Maurice Prendergast: 1959-1924 (Photocopy), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Galley Proofs for Prendergast Essay, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Genealogical Research, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Project Documents, 1983-1986 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Notes, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Outline, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - "Prendergast Addresses,", 1987 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "Prendergast Bibliography" Note Cards, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
  - "Prendergast Lectures: Charles Sheeler,", 1987 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "Prendergast Systematic Catalog General Bibliography and Exhibition Listing,", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Printed Material about Massachusetts (Photocopies), undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Printed Material about Charles and Maurice Prendergast (Photocopies), 1893-1980s; (5 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
  - Project Budget, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Project Reports, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Records of Meetings with Mrs. Prendergast, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Samples of Catalogue Raisonne (Photocopies), 1959-1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Work of Maurice and Charles Prendergast in the Hanging Collection of Mrs. Charles Prendergast,", circa 1983 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Exhibition Files, 1962-circa 1997; Series 6; (Boxes 14-16, 28; 2.0 linear feet)
  This series contains files maintained by Milton Brown documenting his work as curator or contributor to various exhibitions. Included are sets of files for three major exhibitions for which Brown was a curator: the Jacob Lawrence Exhibition at the Whitney Museum, "The Modern Spirit: American Painting and Photography, 1908-1935," for the Arts Council of Great Britain, and "Paintings from the United States from the Museums of Washington" for the Institute of Fine Arts in Mexico. Files for these exhibitions include correspondence, draft writings for the catalog, reports and planning documents, lists of works, research material, and publicity and reviews. Also found are records of the exhibition of Milton Brown's landscape watercolors and records of artwork loaned for exhibition from the Brown's private art collection.
  Additional files in this series document Brown's work on other exhibitions including the 50th Anniversary of the Armory Show. Found here are three interviews regarding the 1963 exhibition including an interview of Milton Brown and Marcel Duchamp conducted by Martha Deane in 1963 for the Martha Deane Show, which aired on WOR, New York, N.Y.; an interview of Brown conducted by Duncan MacDonald for his show, "Observation Point" on Station WNYC, New York, N.Y., April 10, 1963; and an interview of Duchamp conducted in 1963 by Milton Brown for Channel 13, New York, N.Y.
  - Exhibitions of Milton Brown's Artwork, circa 1996-1997; (4 folders) (Box 14, Folder 11-14)
  - Artwork Loaned from Milton Brown's Private Collection, 1969-1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "American Painting 1970-1980," Toledo Museum of Art, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Armory Show: 50th Anniversary Exhibition," Munson-Williams-Proctor Arts Institute, 1962-1963; (4 folders) (Box 14, Folder 17-20)
  - "Armory Show" Interview of Milton Brown by Duncan McDonald, 1963; (1 sound cassette; 1 duplicate sound disk; 1 transcript) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - "Armory Show" Interview of Milton Brown and Marcel Duchamp by Martha Deane, 1963; (1 sound cassette; 1 duplicate sound cassette; 1 transcript) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - "Armory Show" Interview of Marcel Duchamp by Milton Brown, 1963; (1 sound cassette; 1 transcript) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - "Art in the Armory," Lexington Avenue Armory, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "Henry Bernstein: Paintings, Drawings, and Mural Studies," Arnold Klein Gallery, 1982, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Jacob Lawrence Exhibition, Whitney Museum (Box 14)
    - Catalog Materials, circa 1973 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Chronology, circa 1973 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence with Jacob Lawrence, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Lists of Works and Lenders, circa 1973 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Material from C. Alan, circa 1970 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Notes, "Social Realism and Jacob Lawrence,", circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Publicity and Reviews, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Research Material, circa 1973; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
  - "The Modern Spirit: American Painting 1908-1935," Hayward Gallery (Box 14)
    - Bibliography, circa 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Biographies of Artists, circa 1977; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 34-35)
    - Catalog Drafts, circa 1977; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 36-37)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1977; (4 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
    - Lists of Artwork, 1976-1977; (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 5-7)
    - Lists of Photographs, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Loan Forms, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Postcards from Exhibition, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Reports from Assistant, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Reviews, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - "Never Separate from the Heart: Philip Evergood 1901-1973," Bucknell University, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - "The New Spirit: Artist Organizers of the Armory Show," Hirshhorn Museum, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - "The New York Painter, A Century of Teaching: Morse to Hoffman," Marlborough-Gerson Gallery, 1967; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 15-16)
  - "Paintings from the United States from the Museums of Washington," Institute of Fine Arts, Mexico (Box 15)
    - Artist Files, circa 1980; (5 folders) (Box 15, Folder 17-21)
    - Catalog Drafts, 1980; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 22-23)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Expenses, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Floor Plans, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Planning Documents, 1980-1981; (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 27-28)
    - Photographs, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Publicity and Reviews, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Research Files, circa 1930s-1986; Series 7; (Boxes 16-19; 3.0 linear feet)
  This series contains files maintained by Milton and Blanche Brown documenting their research on various topics in art history and architecture. These files do not appear to be associated with specific projects and may have been maintained for regular use for lectures, teaching, and writing projects. Files may include notes written by both Milton and Blanche, printed material from museums, articles and book excerpts (including a large amount of photocopied material), as well as bibliographies and lists. Also found here is a set of files on architecture, primarily containing photocopies of material from various publications. These files appear to have been created around 1979 for an unspecified project. Researchers should note that all of the the folder subject headings in this series are those given by Blanche or Milton Brown and there may be multiple folders where the subjects overlap or have similar headings. For example, there is a file called "Painting, American, Taste" and another called "Patronage and Taste," and the contents of these files may overlap and should both be consulted.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject. A group of files on architecture are arranged alphabetically under the heading "Architecture Subject Files."
  - American Art Collections Lists, 1931, 1986; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - American Art, General, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - American Artists Who Studied in Munich, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - American Literature and Art, circa 1950-1959; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - Architecture, undated; (4 folders) (Box 16, Folder 9-12)
  - Architecture Subject Files (Box 16)
    - Marcel Breuer, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Daniel Burnham, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Carrere and Hastings, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - City Planning, Suburbs, New Towns, Zoning, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Ralph Cram (and His Firms), circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Design, Furniture, etc., circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "Flavor of the Decade" Articles, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Buckminster Fuller, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Cass Gilbert, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Irving Gill, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Bruce Goff, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Bertram Goodhue, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Greene and Greene, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Walter Gropius, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Hardy, Holzman, Pfeiffer, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Raymond Hood, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - George Howe and William Lescaze, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Philip Johnson, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Albert Kahn, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Louis Kahn, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Bernard Maybeck, circa 1979 (Box 16, Folder 33)